[Fate Chooses You]
[Episode 40]
Disciples of Xin Xie Manor
are really unreasonable.
But not to mention you,
if I were given this task
of finding a needle in a haystack,
I wouldn't have time
for this either.
What do you mean?
Looking for a person
in the vast crowd.
You know I'm looking for someone?
Not only do I know who you're looking for,
but I also know
where he is.
Where is he?
How much did you say
that fish cost again?
Seven hundred taels.
I'll scrape together some money
to pay you back.
Is that okay?
That was the price before.
Now,
it's different.
So what will it take
for you to tell me where he is?
As long as you tell me,
I'll do anything.
Anything?
Anything.
I'm thirsty.
I told you there were fish.
And it took the bait.
Where is my fish basket?
What is so good about that War Demon?
Why does a nice girl like you
have to look for him?
Just say it, sir.
What else do you want me to do?
There's no more.
However,
I have one more question.
I'm all ears.
You have been to the divine realm?
Who told you that?
Do not worry about that.
I have been there.
I want to ask you about someone.
Who is it?
A goddess.
A goddess?
What is her name?
I don't know.
Then what is her position?
Is she worshipped anywhere?
I do not know that either.
You don't know anything about her.
How am I supposed to ask around?
To be remembered by you,
she must have some distinct features.
She's beautiful.
She's beautiful?
Yes.
Extremely beautiful.
There are many beautiful girls
in this world.
Those who can become goddesses
are all graceful and outstanding.
How is being beautiful a distinct feature?
Her beauty
is unforgettable.
If you had seen her,
you would definitely remember.
No matter how beautiful she is,
I definitely have not seen her.
Let me put it this way.
I have been to the divine realm,
but I only stayed there
for less than an hour.
I met a fairy child,
chatted with him for a little while,
and then came down.
You didn't see anyone else?
No.
Alright.
I've answered your question.
Now can you tell me
where Lu Qianqiao is?
Don't tell me
you're going back on your word.
Why are you looking for him?
You like him?
I...
How much do you like him?
like him a lot.
I only like him.
If you catch up with him,
and he runs away again,
what will you do?
It's not like he hasn't run before.
I'll just chase him again.
Not bad.
You have some sense.
War Demons are all rigid
and stubborn.
If you want to catch up with him,
you must be more stubborn than him.
Once you catch up with him,
pester him relentlessly,
and never give up.
Remember,
you must be thick-skinned.
You're quite right.
He
always falls for that.
And then?
There's more?
And then,
find a good place.
Like
a deserted island
or deep mountains with no people.
Take him there to stay,
live in seclusion from then on,
and spend the rest of your lives in peace.
Sounds good.
Never mind.
About you releasing my fish this time,
let's forget it.
Remember,
you must take him
to a good place,
live in seclusion,
and spend the rest of your lives in peace.
Just don't ruin my plans again.
You...
aren't in good health, are you?
I devoted myself to the Dao for years
and recently came out of seclusion.
I'm a bit unaccustomed to it.
Well...
You should rest more.
Is there anything else?
No.
You haven't told me
where he is.
I heard the War Demons'
5 curses have been broken.
Now, he
should be able to see colors
and taste flavors, right?
I also heard
that at Zuixian Restaurant in the capital,
there's a gluttonous diner
who likes to eat sweets.
He has been eating there
for almost half a month
and still hasn't tired of them.
I see.
Thanks.
Thank you.
You are a really good person, sir.
And the golden ring on your neck
looks pretty nice.
I'll be going now.
[Zi Fei, Youhu Clan]
Does it look nice?
If your power hadn't been
confined by this thing,
we wouldn't have had to
go to so much trouble.
Do you think that person just now
can lure the War Demons away?
I think so.
We planned for years
and prepared a good show,
only for them to ruin it like this.
What a pity.
[Sacred seed of the Jianmu Tree]
I already told you
Li Mofu won't amount to anything.
Humans
are the weakest,
yet the greediest.
They want to be ruthless
and achieve a great thing,
and they also want to frame it
as great benevolence and righteousness,
trying to gain the world's understanding
and praise.
They want everything,
but end up with nothing.
They wasted
your sacred seed of the Jianmu Tree
for nothing.
However,
we didn't go to all that trouble
for nothing.
At least we know now
that in this world,
there is a Perfect War Demon.
So what if he's a Perfect War Demon?
Isn't he still
tied down by a woman
from the immortal sects?
This is called everything has its match.
That woman from the immortal sect
can keep Lu Qianqiao in check.
Maybe in the future,
you'll also meet someone
who can keep you in check.
Keep me in check?
That person
hasn't been born yet.
[Zuixian Restaurant]
Enjoy, sir.
Miss,
what would you like to eat?
I'm looking for someone,
a man.
He looks about
32 or 33 years old,
very handsome,
and likes sweets.
Miss,
as you can see,
our restaurant is so famous.
With so many guests coming and going
every day,
I really can't remember
the guests' faces.
He booked the whole place a few days ago.
Please try to remember carefully.
Booked the whole place?
There was such a person, I think.
He was quite handsome,
but very cold.
He came to eat at 7 PM every day.
He only tried 5 dishes every time,
preferred not to be disturbed,
and didn't like to talk.
Yes, that's him.
Where is he?
He left.
He left?
Where did he go?
That I don't know.
He only booked the place for half a month.
By my reckoning,
he hasn't been here for 3 days.
He might have left the capital
a long time ago.
Come and take a look.
All homemade.
Miss.
Sir.
-This...
-You want some?
I'd like one.
Come and take a look.
Little pendants,
little trinkets.
Take a look.
Here you go.
Little pendants,
little trinkets here.
Take a look.
Little pendants!
[Mr. Qi]
What are you doing?
Painting.
Did I give you permission to paint me?
You are quite
a funny girl.
How do you know the woman in my painting
is you?
Take a look.
The woman in my painting
has a mole near her eye.
Miss,
do you have it?
You...
You're very good at painting, huh?
I just make a living
with this craft.
Well then,
can you paint a portrait
for me?
I could,
but
my fee is quite high.
That's fine.
I have money.
Alright.
Come on.
Tell me,
who am I painting?
Call them over.
I don't know where he is.
So you can't find him.
That's why you're taking your anger out
on an innocent painter.
I didn't say I wouldn't paint.
Sit.
Describe him.
He is very tall and thin.
As for his looks,
he is well-featured,
and quite handsome.
He has prominent brow bones,
and a straight nose.
He seems a bit
unapproachable.
But once you get to know him,
you'll find he's actually very gentle.
Like a frozen pool,
when warmed,
it turns into a trickling stream.
He likes painting a lot
and is very quiet when he paints.
I think
the saying
"a modest gentleman, gentle as jade"
perfectly describes him.
His smile is very gentle.
His eyes are deep,
like a boundless night sky
filled with bright stars,
brighter than
any star
I've ever seen.
But when he fights,
he's like a different person,
fierce and ruthless.
And his movements
are very neat and stylish,
like a martial hero.
As long as he's around,
any problem becomes simple.
Even if the mountains collapse,
or the seas flood the land,
as long as I can look at him,
I feel at peace.
Feel at peace?
Why did you stop painting?
I can't do it.
Why?
Miss,
look at your description.
Does this sound like a human?
Are we still doing this or not?
We are.
Then here's what we are going to do.
I'll ask,
and you answer.
What's his face shape?
Square or round?
Long or flat?
I guess it's round,
but not entirely.
His features are sharp.
His cheeks are a bit thin.
His lips are thick.
His smile is warm
and friendly.
What about his eyes?
Almond eyes, phoenix eyes,
or peach blossom eyes?
They are almond eyes when he's relaxed.
They look sharp when he stares.
When he frowns,
he looks affectionate and reserved.
I think I've seen this man before.
You have?
Where?
I think I've seen him.
In this restaurant across the street.
He was drinking there.
Miss,
let me give you some advice.
Stay in the city today.
There's a lantern festival tonight.
If he's in the city,
he'll surely join the fun.
I will definitely stay.
There is a lantern festival?
Take it.
[Yonghua Gate]
Come take a look!
Miss,
would you like to buy a mask?
Take a look.
Come take a look!
Masks! Masks!
Beautiful War Demon masks!
Sir,
would you like to buy a mask?
No, thanks.
Sir,
did any catch your eye?
No, thanks.
Come on, take a look.
Miss,
see anything you like?
Come and take a look!
Here, try this.
Okay.
Miss, what would you like to eat?
I'll have a bowl of flour tea
and a plate of sweet cakes.
I'm terribly sorry.
The sweet cakes are sold out.
Sold out?
Yes.
A customer came by just now
and bought all the sweet cakes
in my shop.
Looking at his build,
he didn't look like a big eater.
Sir,
what did he look like?
I was busy
packing his order,
so I didn't look closely.
I only remember
he looked travel-worn,
like a traveler from far away.
Then take a look.
Does he look like this man?
Their builds are very similar.
Where did he go?
He went that way, I remember.
Thank you, sir.
You're welcome.
Sachets! Sachets!
♪ Spending a lifetime,
I ask myself what I first sought ♪
Lu Qianqiao,
if one day—
♪ What is it my heart truly desires? ♪
I mean if—
you were also affected
by Ghost Covering Eyes,
♪ Step by step up the immortal stairway ♪
would you completely
forget about me
and not remember me at all?
♪ Paved with countless lost souls ♪
How could that happen?
What if?
♪ Who would dare destroy the ladder
to immortality and end the path? ♪
What if?
If that day really comes,
I will go find you,
♪ The sun blazes over the earth ♪
and we'll get to know each other
all over again.
Sorry.
♪ Yet it cannot warm
every cold home below ♪
♪ I've heard cries that rend the heavens ♪
Excuse me.
This person—
♪ I hear the shame of parting ♪
have you seen him?
No, I haven't.
♪ This immortal path admired by all ♪
♪ Can exist, or not exist ♪
♪ Once again I see
the world's cold indifference ♪
♪ Bending everyone's spine ♪
♪ Illusions and vanity blind the eyes,
how could one still care ♪
Lu Qianqiao!
♪ Don't think I'm ridiculous and foolish ♪
Catch him! He's a War Demon!
♪ My solitary voice
will echo through the valley ♪
Catch him!
♪ They speak of immortal grace
and mystic arts ♪
Catch him!
♪ Is there still a trace
of compassion? ♪
♪ Realize my heart
seeks no personal gain ♪
Hurry up!
Catch him!
Stop right there!
♪ Realize my hands
remain unstained by blood ♪
♪ Realize this life still,
as always, pursues the Dao ♪
So beautiful!
♪ Having seen the widespread devastation ♪
♪ How could I look on and ignore it? ♪
♪ I do not fear returning to dust ♪
♪ I walk this path alone ♪
♪ To let all walk ♪
♪ The road to immortality ♪
♪ I fear not defying
immortal laws and sacred precepts ♪
♪ Let sin be punished,
let desire be destroyed ♪
Lanterns!
Beautiful lanterns!
♪ Yet the heart must never be forsaken ♪
Be careful!
Look!
This person is so amazing!
She must be a cultivator.
What a coincidence, miss.
We meet again.
Judging by your reaction,
I'm afraid you haven't found
the person you're looking for
and mistook me
for him.
Why are you crying?
No, I...
I was just kidding.
I
hate seeing girls cry the most.
I don't need you to comfort me.
Sorry.
Actually,
I understand
the pain of looking for someone.
I don't need you to comfort me.
I'm not.
It's true.
I'm also looking for someone.
I've been looking for so many years,
but still haven't found her.
Can you drink?
Why?
We are in the same situation.
Naturally, we should comfort
our sorrows with wine
and get drunk together.
[Zuixian Restaurant]
Here's the wine.
Our signature wine,
"Never Returning Home."
The name of this wine
is quite interesting.
Mr. Qi, you have a good eye.
You know I'm Mr. Qi?
Of course.
Our wine
is unparalleled.
But good quality comes at a price.
This fine wine
costs 3 taels per jar.
Three taels per jar?
Don't worry about the money.
Bring as much as you have.
Alright!
You're quite generous.
Can you keep drinking?
Yes.
Let's drink.
Keep going.
You don't get drunk easily.
You can really hold your liquor.
Let me tell you.
Actually,
I'm not a good drinker.
I can't hold my liquor.
There's someone else
who can.
Let me guess.
Could it be
the one you're looking for?
How do you know?
Why don't you tell me
what other characteristics he has
besides being handsome
and dashing?
If one day
I run into him,
I'll definitely keep him for you.
There are too many.
I'll say,
and you remember.
I'll remember.
He
loves drinking,
and he can hold his liquor.
Even if he drinks all of this,
he won't get drunk.
And he loves delicious food,
all kinds of them,
especially sweets.
He's a bit cold to strangers.
But he's very nice to his friends.
He's also good at painting.
His paintings
are much better than yours.
Better than mine?
He's also proficient in medicine.
Anyway, there's nothing he can't do.
He knows a little bit of everything.
Have you remembered it?
I have.
Also...
I like him.
He used to like me too.
We've been to many places together,
from the Central Plains to North Xiang.
We've eaten
lots of delicious food together,
♪ Caught in fate's design,
I search my soul ♪
watched many sunrises together,
♪ What should I do to avoid
living my life in vain? ♪
been outlaws together,
and faced death together.
♪ My blade stays clean,
untouched by dust ♪
♪ Yet it's sparked thousands of wars ♪
Senior.
Senior!
How do we get to the pantry
at Li Ying Garden?
♪ A towering tree worn down into
a blade devoid of feeling ♪
I am Xin Mei from Xin Xie Manor.
May I know your name, Senior?
♪ The heart hides its root
at the bottom of the abyss ♪
Lu Qianqiao.
Qian as in thousands,
♪ In red, I look at you
with a glimpse of shame ♪
and Qiao as in arbor trees.
Since you call me Senior,
I won't let you die.
♪ Being haunted by the spell,
even if it's cruel ♪
Thank you for saving my life, Mr. Lu.
I will never forget your favor.
If you ever need help,
♪ It's better than being trapped by fate ♪
I'll come to your aid
despite any danger.
♪ Between gain and loss ♪
♪ Lies a thousand years of grace ♪
I don't need you to go through any danger.
It'll save me a lot of trouble
if you could
master the Fish Drinking Technique soon.
♪ Even if it's soul-eroding,
extreme pain, I accept it all ♪
What exactly should I call you?
♪ Embracing pain as home,
reborn like a phoenix ♪
Are you Lu Huai,
the magistrate of Wei County,
or the Autumn Crimson Blade,
a hero from the martial world,
♪ Just to trade the rest of my days
for one true life as a human ♪
or Lu Qianqiao, a War Demon?
Lu Qianqiao,
♪ Let strong wine carry me into
drunken nights till midnight ♪
you are a War Demon, aren't you?
♪ Let my soul blaze in brilliant colors ♪
Yes.
♪ Let the agony of a thousand cuts ♪
The War Demons
are all evil.
♪ Stand as proof that I have lived ♪
You're a disciple of an immortal sect.
I am a remnant of the War Demons.
It's only natural
♪ Let me taste a life of flesh and blood
in full ♪
that you want to kill me.
♪ Let me savor the many flavors
of the mortal world ♪
But ask yourself this:
have I ever harmed you?
♪ Let me face the world's
warmth and cold alike ♪
Have I ever hurt you?
I promise,
♪ To live and perish with it,
daring to go mad, daring to dream ♪
though I am one of the War Demons,
I don't want to be a War Demon.
I only want to be human.
♪ Let strong wine carry me into
drunken nights till midnight ♪
For my wish,
I shed my skin,
♪ Let my soul blaze in brilliant colors ♪
renewed my bones,
and changed my flesh.
Every time I succeed
at one of these things,
♪ Let the agony of a thousand cuts ♪
my cultivation
would decrease significantly.
♪ Stand as proof that I have lived ♪
But I'm still happy
that I can see
this colorful world,
♪ Let me taste a life of flesh and blood
in full ♪
and that I can feel pain.
And this feeling makes me
♪ Let me savor the many flavors
of the mortal world ♪
feel truly alive.
♪ Let me face the world's
warmth and cold alike ♪
♪ To live and perish with it,
daring to go mad, daring to dream ♪
Let's go back to Wei County.
That's my hometown.
You've lived there too.
♪ Don't live in vain,
have a pleasant journey of life ♪
You mean...
you're willing to be a mortal
with me
and give up cultivating altogether?
My Dao heart is unstable anyway.
I probably won't achieve much
on this path of cultivation.
Xin Mei,
thank you.
Thank you.
Then why did he
leave you behind
and go alone?
He didn't leave me behind.
Something happened later,
and he forgot me.
Lu Qianqiao...
Lu Qianqiao!
Lu Qianqiao, don't go!
I'm Xin Mei! Come back!
Lu Qianqiao!
No!
But I will remember.
I will always remember.
I remember he said
he wanted
to go to the most expensive restaurant
in the capital...
Taste the finest dishes,
drink the strongest wine,
get completely drunk,
and have a good sleep.
I'll remember
every promise I made to him
and every word I said.
Then,
I will find him.
I will definitely find him.
Definitely...
I definitely will.
Finding someone
in the vast sea of people...
is no easy task.
Where on earth is she?
Miss,
you're awake?
You ordered so many jars of wine
last night.
I thought you had a great tolerance,
but you slept straight through till dawn.
Excuse me, where is
the gentleman who came with me?
He left.
Check, please.
That gentleman already paid.
Oh, right.
The gentleman said
your painting
was soaked in wine last night.
He left a new one for you.
Oh, right.
Could you tell me how to get to the pier?
Why don't you believe me?
That Crazy Taoist's reading
was wrong.
People born on September 9th
are not the Heavenly Talent.
People born on August 16th are.
You know?
See? What a coincidence.
It happens to be your birthday.
I see that your
forehead
is long and full,
broad and wide.
This is clearly the face
of a capable person
with great wealth and honor.
Let me tell you,
if you go to Lingji Mountain,
you will definitely ascend
to godhood in the future.
You know?
How about this?
I won't ask for much.
Just give me 5 taels of silver,
and I'll write you a recommendation letter
to cultivate immortality
at Lingji Mountain.
Sounds good?
I'm not going.
You have a natural Daoist physique.
If you don't cultivate immortality,
what do you want to do?
I'll go to Yandu
to learn how to build dragon boats.
What's there to learn
about building boats?
Don't you think so?
This silly child.
Home-brewed wine!
Stop wandering around.
It's time for boarding.
Hurry up.
[Zhoudu Pier]
Are you going to Yanzhou?
Yes.
Didn't you say
you were sailing to Xiangzhou?
Yes.
I go wherever I want.
It's none of your business.
Sir,
please board the ship.
Here.
What are you going to Yanzhou for, sir?
Visiting relatives and friends,
or doing business?
Yanzhou is a great place.
No extreme heat in summer,
and no severe cold in winter.
The Rice Noodles with Lamb there
are known far and wide.
As for the scenery of Lake Boyang,
it's like a view from heaven.
Are we leaving or not?
We're leaving.
We're leaving right now.
Sir.
My boat is small and profits are low.
Can I take another passenger
to earn a bit more?
Miss!
Are you going to Yanzhou?
There's great food
and beautiful scenery there!
Chu Ying?
Are we leaving or not?
♪ Caught in fate's design,
I search my soul ♪
♪ What should I do to avoid
living my life in vain? ♪
♪ My blade stays clean,
untouched by dust ♪
♪ Yet it's sparked thousands of wars ♪
♪ Even if it's soul-eroding,
collarbone-binding pain, I accept it all ♪
♪ Embracing pain as home,
reborn like a phoenix ♪
♪ Just to trade the rest of my days
for one true life as a human ♪
♪ Let strong wine carry me into
drunken nights till midnight ♪
♪ Let my soul blaze in brilliant colors ♪
♪ Let the agony of a thousand cuts ♪
♪ Stand as proof that I have lived ♪
Miss,
are you going?
Yes.
♪ Let me taste a life of flesh and blood
in full ♪
I'm going!
♪ Let me savor the many flavors
of the mortal world ♪
♪ Let me face the world's
warmth and cold alike ♪
♪ To live and perish with it,
daring to go mad, daring to dream ♪
♪ Don't live in vain,
have a pleasant journey of life ♪
If you really can't accept it,
how about 3 taels of silver?
For 3 taels of silver,
I'll let you become an immortal.
An immortal!
Master.
Your child
can't tell good from bad.
Listen to me.
Don't go to Yandu.
Take him to
cultivate immortality at Lingji Mountain.
Otherwise,
it'd be a waste of
his talent.
Master,
he is a swindler.
You little brat.
He said the prophecy was wrong.
The Heavenly Talent born on September 9th
is not the savior of the world.
The one born on August 16th is.
That's the truth.
He is right.
Exactly.
People born on September 9th
are saviors of the world.
Those born on August 16th
are also saviors of the world.
Those born on May 4th
and March 2nd
are all saviors of the world.
Among all living beings in this world,
as long as you choose justice,
shoulder responsibilities,
stay true to yourself,
and believe in yourself,
you can be a savior of the world.
You...
Crazy Taoist?
[The End]